BANGARU LAKSHMAN

Autodesk Certified Professional : Revit Mep Mechanical Mechanical Bim Modeler / Mep Cad Drafting Engg

Email: bangaru_laxman_hvac@yahoo.com Cell no: +91 9948596054, +965 67795467

Career Objective:

To make optimum use of my skills and capabilities in a reputable organization, which offers me a chance to grow and enhance my career opportunities, and to be a part of team where I can contribute my skills and experience in the success of the company.

Total Experience:

Having Total 12 Years of experience in Mep Filed 4 yrs in Revit Mep, Navisworks & 8 Yrs in Mep Autocad Drafting both in Middle East and in India.

Bim Modelling & Naviswork Job Responsibilities:

- o Revit, Navisworks Using 4D stimulations for Materials Planning and Management.
- o Revit, Navisworks Improving Models to Enhance 4D Stimulations for construction Planning.
- o Attending Bim Workshop meetings & Visit to Site for variations between drawings & Site.
- o Worked Bim Projects on LOD 300 & 500.
- o Creating walkthrough path in revit.
- o Clash checking both in Revit Interface & Navis Manage.
- o Create Viewpoints & comments in Navis.
- o Preparation of central file location.
- o Transfer projects standards, Copy Monitor, Creating Floor Plans.
- Create shared parameters.
- o Creating Work sets, as per disciplines, creating Templates & sheets.
- Creating sub disciplines from the filters.
- Developing 3D Models and annotation from Design 2D Drawings.
- o Creating and developing Revit Basic families.
- o Developing mep coordination models and sections.
- o Quantity takeoff by using Revit schedules & Navis Quantification.
- o Preparing Spaces, Placing Spaces, Zone Color Schemes and Airflow Schedules.
- o Producing Sprinkler Design Schedules.

Design Job Responsibilities:

- o Preparing IFC drawing to Shop Level drawing.
- o Preparation of Hvac shop, design & Detail dwgs. As per ashrea and smacna.
- o Duct sizing as per constant friction & Velocity reduction method Mcquay Software.
- o Chilled water pipe selection by using Mcquay Software.
- o Selection of Air Terminals.
- o Hvac Duct & Chilled water Routing and Location of Out lets.
- o Preparing shop drawing for Chiller plant room & Cooling tower details drawings.
- o Developing single line into Double line duct routing.
- o Preparation of Schematic Diagrams and Riser Diagrams.
- o Preparing the schedules.
- o False ceiling co-ordination (Electrical lights, diffusers &sprinklers)
- o Preparing builders work dwgs (Slab openings, core wall openings, wall openings).
- o Preparing Shaft Co-ordination of MEP services.
- o Raising RFI's based on Specification and Design Drawing.
- o Preparing as built dwgs of Hvac, drainage, water supply and firefighting services.
- Prepare architecture drawings for xrefs.

Professional Experience:

- Working as Mechanical Bim Modeler in Omnix International LLC. (Kuwait)
 From March 2019 to Till Date.
- Worked as Mechanical Bim Modeler in Mitsubishi Heavy Industries. (Qatar)
 From October 2017 to October 2018.
- Worked as Mechanical Bim Modeler in Worley Parsons (Qatar)
 From Aug 2015 to July 2017
- Worked as Mechanical Bim Modeler / Mep Cad Drafting Engineer in L&T Construction Pvt. Ltd. (India)
 From Sep 2011 to July 2015.
- Worked as Mep Cad Drafting Engineer in ETA ENGINEERING Pvt. Ltd. (India)
 From March-2010 to August 2011.
- Worked as a Mep Cad Drafting Engineer in BLUE STAR INDIA Pvt. Ltd. (India)
 From March-2008 to Feb-2010
- Worked as a Mep Cad Drafting Engineer) in S.S.COMFORT LINE (Carrier Dealer) India From Feb-2006 to March-2008.

Software:

Applications : MS-Office, Mcquay Software

Revit & CAD Packages : Autocad, REVIT MEP, Navis Freedom, Navis Manage, Autodesk Vault,

MEP key Skills : MEP Cad coordination, HVAC, Electrical & Fire fighting.

Key Projects Involved:

Project Name: Qatar Underground Metro Project, Doha, Qatar.

Work Description: MEP Bim Modelling Using Revit, and AutoCAD Software, Mep Drafting.

Project Name: Northgate Mall, Qatar (Working Through India). Work Description: : Mep Layouts Using AutoCAD Software.

Project Name: Hyderabad Metro Rail Project, Hyderabad, India.

Consultant: AECOM, India

Work Description: Mep Layouts Using Revit and AutoCAD Software, Mep Drafting.

Project Name: Apollo Hospital Hyderabad, India.

Consultant: Spectral Consultants.

Work Description: Mep Layouts by using software Auto-CAD.

Project Name: Franklin Templeton, Hyderabad (IT Park), India.

Consultant: Prasad Escendo consultancy (Hyderabad).

Work Description: Mep Layouts by using software Auto-CAD.

Achievements: Top Performer in Year 2012-2013 Employees Rating at L&T Construction.

Top Performer in Year 2013-2014 Employees Rating at L&T Construction.

Skype user id: lakshmanbangaru1

Educational Qualification:

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering N.C.V.T in Diesel Mechanic